nr-apps.com 2015-06-08

# Privacy Policy | nr-apps.com Magento modules & extensions

Netresearch App Factory AG (hereinafter called “nr-apps.com”) provides a variety of services on and via the website: 

a webshop, a clients' portal, a clients' forum 

As a consequence, information of different kinds are exchanged. This mainly concerns data which arises when a formu´s or blog´s user uploads information, puts it online or displays it for other users. These information are partially personal data. Of course nr-apps.com, heeds the regulations of the Federal Data Protection Act and of the German Teleservices Act and will only collect and process personal data within the limits of the following data privacy statement. 

If the customer's consent is requested in conjunction with the services, it will be granted by clicking the respective checkbox or by sending the comment within the scope of the blog comment function. The consent allows for the client's personal data to be collected, processed and used. The consent can of course be taken back at any time. 

The withdrawal of consent in written form is to be addressed to: 

Netresearch App Factory AG  
Nonnenstrasse 11c  
04229 Leipzig  
E-Mail: info@nr-apps.com 

nr-apps.com points out that some services and functions can no longer be used after the withdrawal of consent. 

## THE DATA PRIVACY STATEMENT IS AVAILABLE.

#### 1\. Kind and scope of the collection and processing of personal data

Personal data are collected and processed when the registration for individual services of the website is accomplished or a comment is made in the blog. Data arising from the use of our website will be saved and in this way collected to a certain extent but anonymised or pseudoanonymised. The data given in the clients' forum and the blog after registration will be saved on the servers electronically in order to make the data available to third parties to the desired extent. 

#### 2\. Inventory data in the clients' forum

As stated above, the website provides several services with different goals. In terms of the collected inventory data the following differentiation is crucial: 

##### 2.1 Purchase of products and services in the shop

Prior to the purchase of products in the online shop registration is required. The access data to the clients' portal is provided in the course of registration. In the course of this the following inventory data are generally requested or saved, respectively: 

_Given name and surname, Gender, Address, E-mail address, Phone number, Commercial Register Number, Tax ID_

The data are needed for the identification as a contractual partner, for the creation and management of the client's account, furthermore to be able to send products to the customer and to be able to contact them if necessary. 

Moreover, the e-mail address will be used to send information on the offers if the respective checkbox has been clicked. 

If the client provided the complete access data to their webshop, these data will solely be collected, saved and used to process immediate requests owed under the contract and to help solve problems. They will also be used to carry out other client's requests or if they are required for other contractual purposes. 

##### 2.2 Clients' forum

If a client registers with the clients' forum the following information will be gathered in terms of storage and collection in addition to the above mentioned: user name used in the clients' forum and photo and personal signature if this option was selected. 

##### 2.3 Storage and accessibility of the contract

nr-apps.com saves the contract and emails the order data to the customers. The General Terms and Conditions of Trade can also be accessed [here](http://www.nr-apps.com/store/terms-and-conditions/) by the clients at any time. The customer can view their previous orders in the clients' login area. 

#### 3\. E-mail newsletter

If the client decided to subscribe to an e-mail newsletter the e-mail address the newsletter is sent to will be stored and used for the mailing of the newsletter. The client is free to cancel the subscription at any time by clicking the respective link at the bottom of the newsletter. 

#### 4\. Usage data, usage profiles, cookies

The nr-apps.com website can be accessed at any time. No personal data must be provided to do so. In the course of this the data mentioned below will arise, though. The following regulations apply to these data: 

When visiting the website the IP address, the times of start and end of the visit, the submitted amount of data and the subpages that were visited are saved in the so- called logfiles. These logfiles are collected and stored for security purposes in order to be able to track cases of misuse. Furthermore, insights into user behaviours regarding the nr-apps.com webpages are gained statistically and anonymously. The client can contradict the collection, storage and use of their data at any time. 

When using the webpages, information on the browser type, version, date and time of the visit and the cookie number are gathered by using cookies. If the client wishes to prohibit the use of cookies, they can stop the storage of cookies over their browser. The details on this can be viewed in the documentation or in the browser's help function. 

#### 5\. Content data

If the client puts postings, pictures and other contents in the clients' forum or if postings and other contents are commented and the client communicates with other clients within the scope of the clients' forum these contents and postings will be stored and made accessible in the internet. Personal data will of course also be given in this context. The client can decide themselves which of the information are to be revealed, however. The posted contents remain accessible even if the client cancels their user agreement with us by deleting their account. Via e-mail the client can demand anonymisation or even deletion of these contents, however. 

#### 6\. Dissemination of content data to third parties or the public

nr-apps.com disseminates data to third parties if it is necessary for the fulfillment of the contract or for the enforcement of rights and duties. Content data will also be disseminated if a government body, and especially prosecuting authorities, requests these data and if the dissemination of the data is required for the defence against hazards to the public security and public policy and for the prosecution of criminal acts provided that the respective judical writs are existent or if by law nr-apps.com is otherwise obliged to provide the data. 

#### 7\. Social media plugins

On our website social plugins (“plugins”) of the social network facebook.com are used which is operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (“Facebook”). The plugins can be recognized by one of the Facebook logos (white “f“ on blue square or “thumbs up“ sign) or by their marking “Facebook social plugin”. The list and the look of the Facebook social plugins can be viewed here: <http://developers.facebook.com/plugins>. 

The client's browser will set up a direct connection to the Facebook servers if they visit one of our websites containing plugins of the above-mentioned kind. Facebook will transmit the plugin's content directly to the browser which will then incorporate it in the website. As a result, we cannot wield influence on the scope of the data collected by these Facebook plugins. That is why we inform our clients according to our level of knowledge about: 

Facebook gets informed about clients visiting our respective websites by the use of plugins. Facebook can assign the visit to the respective Facebook account if a client logs on to Facebook. The client's browser will transmit the respective information directly to Facebook if a client interacts with the plugins, e.g. by pressing the like button or sharing a comment. Facebook will save this information. Even if the client is no Facebook member Facebook can find out and save their IP address. 

The following information can be accessed over the Facebook data protection regulations: <http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>: goal and scope of the data collection, information on further processing and use of clients' data by Facebook, clients' rights relating to this and privacy controls. 

Clients who are Facebook members must log off from Facebook before visiting one of our websites unless they accept that Facebook collects their data and links them with their stored member data. Facebook social plugins can be blocked by browser add-ons, e.g. with the “Facebook blocker“. 

#### 8\. Creation of pseudonymous user profiles for web analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service by Google Inc. (“Google“) based in 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA (hereinafter called “Google”). 

Google Analytics uses text files, the so-called "cookies", which are saved onto the client's computer in order to enable the analysis of the client's use of the website. The cookie-generated information on the use of the website are usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA where they are stored. The IP address is trimmed by Google within EU member states or in other contractual states of the Agreement on the European Economic if the IP anonymisation is set active on the website. The complete IP address will only be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and trimmed there in exceptional cases. Google will use these information on behalf of the website operator in order to analyse the use of the website, to draw up reports on the activities on the website and to render further services connected with the use of the internet and the website to the website operator. 

The IP address transmitted by the client's browser in the context of Google Analytics will not be linked with other data by Google. 

Clients can stop the storage of cookies by adjusting the respective functions of their browser software. Please note that in this case certain website functions may not be available to the full extent. Furthermore, clients can stop the collection of the cookie- created data which is related to their use of the website (incl. their IP address) and the processing of these data by Google by downloading and installing the following browser plugin: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>. 

#### 9\. Links to other webpages

nr-apps.com will not assume responsibility for the processing of personal data if the nr-apps.com website contains links to other websites that are not related to it. nr-apps.com cannot wield influence on the processing of personal data that may have been transmitted when the link was clicked. 

#### 10\. Information/ correction / deletion/ blocking

According to the Federal Data Protection Act the client has the right to receive free information about their stored data. Moreover, the client has the opportunity to have the data corrected, blocked and/ or deleted unless these data are needed to fulfil the contract or issued tasks or if these data are required for the enforcement of rights or if the data must be preserved by law. 

#### 11\. Safety

nr-apps.com uses technical and organisational safety measures to secure clients' personal data against loss, false alterations and unauthorized access by third parties.
